Guide to the Queer Zines, Magazines, and Newspapers Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Queer zines, magazines, and newspapers collection
1948-2011
MS 1847
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
The Queer Zines, Magazines, and Newspaper Collection includes printed ephemera and publications documenting the development of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer communities in their own voices. Includes mass circulation and small press publications.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Larry Kramer Initiative Executive Coordinator, 2004-2005. Gift of Bert Hansen, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Queer Zines, Magazines, and Newspaper Collection includes printed ephemera and publications documenting the development of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer communities in their own voices. Includes mass circulation and small press publications.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in one section, Original Accession, 1948, 1974-2004, and two additions.
Bisexuals; Homosexuality; Lesbianism; Transsexualism; LGBTQ resource
- Original Accession, 1948, 1974-2011
  - 11x14 or smaller
    - A Mi Manera (La Vida De Un Homosexual) [Tony Martinez], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adversary, no. 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Advocate, issues 594, 596, 606, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Agony, nos. 1-2, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anything That Moves, issues 1-7, 9-15 and ephemera [previously ], 1991-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 5 - 8)
    - Bay Area Bisexual Network Newsletter, 8 issues, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Beautiful Men [Crawford Barton], 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bed Pan Journal, no. 2, 1992 summer (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Beef! Pictorial, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bikini Kill Girlpower, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bimbox, nos. 1-2, 4-5 (special condensed edition), [1990], undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Bisexuality Study Questionnaire" [Ronald Fox], 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bitch, Butch, Black & Bad, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bitch Queen, no. 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Black Lace, no. 1, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Black Lesbian Newsletter, 4 issues including vol. 1, issues 3-4, 6, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Boy with gun, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Boysville U.S.A., 3 issues including vol. 1, nos. 1-2, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Brains, vol. 1, no. 1, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Brat Attack, nos. 4-5, 1993, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bundle of Sticks, nos. 2, 4-6, 1992, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - The Butch Manual [Clark Henley], 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Campfire, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cards and flyers [assorted], 1984-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Carrie, nos. 1-2, 1991, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Chainsaw, nos. 2-3, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Ciao!, no. 2, 1991 July (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Cops Hate Poetry, vol. 1, no. 10, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Core, vol. 1, issue 1, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 31a)
    - Counting Down [Sarah Van Arsdale], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Cultrix, nos. 1-2, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Curve, vol. 6, no. 2, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Dance Magazine Annual '81, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Deneuve, vol. 2, no. 5; vol. 3, nos. 1-2, 5; vol. 4, no. 1; catalogue, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Double Bill, 2 issues including no. 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Drag Queen Rock Star, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - D.B.D.T.D.: Dumb Bitch Deserves To Die, no. 2, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Dyke Review, 2 issues, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - The Dysfunctional Family Circus, nos. 8a, 11b, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Ecce Queer, vol. 1, no. 2, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 88 Chins, 2 issues, 1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Der Entkleidete Holländer [Jan Swinkels], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Eugenics of the Post-Modern, no. 2, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "An Evening with bell hooks..." poster, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Evil, premier issue, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Evil Taco, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Experiment in Words, vol. 2, no. 8, [1992] (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Fabulous Babes, nos. 1-2, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Factsheet Five, nos. 41, 43, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Fantastic Fanzine, 2 issues, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Felix, vol. 1, no.1, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Feminist Arts News, vol. 3, no. 9, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Fertile La Toyah Jackson Magazine, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - First Hand, vol. 4, nos. 5-6, 8, 1984 May-August (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - F.O.D.: Fatal Over Dose Maggotzine, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Fogtown Rag, vol. 1, no.1, 1990-1991 winter (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - The Fold, 1 issue, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Friday 8 May, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Frighten the Horses, nos. 1, 4-7, 10, 1990-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 61 - 62)
    - Fuh Cole, no. 2, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Fuzzbox, 2 issues including vol. 2, no. 5, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Gai Pied Hebdo, nos. 261, 295, 336, 339, 349/350-352, 354, 361-363 [plus special photo issue], pre-1988-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 65 - 67)
    - Gary Monster Magazine, nos. 14, 20, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Gawk, nos. 4-5, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Gay Black Female, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Gay Skinhead Movement Newsletter, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - G.B. Jones Retrospective, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - The Gentlewomen of California, nos. 6-7, undated (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Getting Too Big for our Niches, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Girl Germs, 2 issues, undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Girlfrenzy, no. 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - G.J.: GirlJock, nos. 2, 5, undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - God Is Gay: An Evolutionary Spiritual Work [Ezekiel Wright, Daniel Inesse], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Hangy Thing, no. 3, undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Health Sharing, vol. 12, no. 4, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Hell's Kitchen, issue 1, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Hidden Perfection, vol. 1, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Hippie Dick, no. 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Hissy Fit, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Hollywood's Queerest Horror Movies, vols. 1-2, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Holy Titclamps, nos. 8-11, including 2 issues of, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Homocore, nos. 3-4, 7, 1989, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Homoture, nos. 1-4, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Hot Lava Monster, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - i am, no. 3, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - i hate gays (and lesbians don't exist), 1992 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Image (San Francisco Examiner), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - In The Family, vol. 5, no. 2, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - In Your Face [publication of the Center for Racial Education], vol. 1, issue 1, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - In Your Face: Political Activism Against Gender Oppression, no. 2, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Intent To Kill, vol. 1, issue 1, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - International Male, 1 issue, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - IQ, undated (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - JD's, 3 issues, undated (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Kill My Love, undated (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Kingdom, vol. 2, no. 1, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Larry Stanton: Painting and Drawing, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - The Latter History & Subsequent Burning of Little Red Riding Hood, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 102a)
    - Lezzie Smut, vol. 1, issue 3, undated (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Lickerish: Polymorphous Queer Candy, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Logomotive, no. 1, undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Made in U. S., vol. 1, no. 1, undated (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Madonna/Ho, undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - MadWoman, nos. 1-2, 1990, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Magazine, no. 8/9, 1984 November (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - The Manhattan Review of Unnatural Acts, nos. 40, 46 [STH], 1977, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Manscape, vol. 1, no. 2, 1985 January (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Manzanas: Tratado de pomofilia, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Meandyke, no. 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Mind Theater, vol. 2, no. 1, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Modern Words, no. 8, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Molière et Louis-Henry Daquin, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Monstar, no. 9, undated (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - Mudflap, 3 issues, undated (Box 7, Folder 118)
    - Murder Can Be Fun, no. 9/10, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 119)
    - My Comrade/Sister, undated (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - My Jodie Book, undated (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Negativa, nos. 1-5, 1991, undated (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - New Uranian, nos. 2, 3/4, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - No External Compulsion, no. 5, undated (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - NYQ, premiere; nos. 1, 6, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - Odyssey Magazine, vol. 2, no. 2, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - The Official 1995 Drag King Calendar (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - On Our Backs, vol. 6, no. 1; vol. 9, nos. 1-3, 1989-1993 (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - On Our Rag, 4 issues including nos. 3-4, plus sticker, Circa 1991 (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Out, 4 issues including no. 1, 1992, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Out Write 90, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Outlook: National Gay and Lesbian Quarterly, nos. [1-3], 5-6, 8-11, 14, 16, 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 132 - 135)
    - Outpunk, nos. 1-2, undated (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - Outweek, assorted issues, letter from editor, copy of article, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 137 - 140)
    - The Overground, vol. 1, no. 1, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Pansybeat, no. 3, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Pavement of Surface, no. 6/9, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - PC Casualties, nos. 1-2, undated (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Personal ad response, undated (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - Piss Elegant, no. 1 [reissue], 1991 (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Planet Roc, vol. 3, no. 3, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Pride 04, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Princess Witch Boy, #2, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 148a)
    - Pup, no. 3, undated (Box 10, Folder 149)
    - Purr-version/ Vagina Dentata, undated (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - Pussy Grazer, 2 issues, undated (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Q San Francisco, no. 12, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - QFM: Queer Fuckers Magazine, nos. 1, 3-4, undated (Box 10, Folder 153)
    - Q.T.: Queer Terrorist Queer Tapette, nos. 2-3, undated (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - Queer City: The Portable Lower East Side, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - Queer L.A., vol. 1, nos. 2-3, 6-7, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - Queer with Class: The First Book of Homocult, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - Quim, nos. 2-5, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - R.F.D., Winter 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Rant & Rave, vol. 1, nos. 2, 4, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - "Rebel Angel", 1987 (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Rock Against Sexism, vol. 4, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Rocketdyke, nos. 1, 3, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Satan Knows His Bride Is Waiting to Take Her With Him to Heaven, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - SCAB, 2 issues, undated (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Scream Box, nos. 1-2, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - Seven in a Barn, undated (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Shebang, no. 2, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Shocking Pink, issue 11, undated (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Shut Up & Love the Rain, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 169a)
    - Siegler, Bobbie [poetry], 1987, undated (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - Sinister Wisdom, nos. 25, 31, 36-39, 1984-1990 (Box 11, Folder 171 - 172)
    - Siren, nos. 1-2, undated (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Sister Nobody, 3 issues, undated (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Skin on Skin, no. 2, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Slut Mag, including bookmark, undated (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - "Song of the Loon", undated (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - "Spew-The Homographic Convergence" [flyer], 1991 (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Square Peg, 5 issues, 1983, 1984, 1986, undated (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Steam, vol. 1, no. 1, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Still Breathing: Canada's Kate Bush Fanzine, vol. 3, no. 3, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Su Madre, premiere issue, undated (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - Susan Minimag, vol. 2, [1993] (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - Swerve, vol. 1, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - Tang!, vol 1, no. 1; vol 2, no 1, 1991, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Tantrum, 2 issues, undated (Box 12, Folder 186)
    - Taste of Latex, vol. 1, nos. 1, 4; no. 8, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - Ted, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - Tema International, issue 2, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - 10 Percent, no. 1, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - There's a Halo That Covers My Balls, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Thing, nos. 1-2, 4-8, 10, 1989-1993 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - Three Dollar Bill, nos. 1-2, [1991] (Box 12, Folder 193)
    - 3,000 Eyes Are Watching Me, undated (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - The Unmentionable, no. 13, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 195)
    - Up Our Butts, issue 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 196)
    - Vanilla Milkshake, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Venus Castina, vol. 1, no. 1, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Vice, vol. 1, issue 4; vol. 2, issues 9, 11; vol. 3, issues 6-7, 1994, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Whorezine, nos. 2-3, 7, 9, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 200)
    - Wicked Women, vol. 1, no. 6, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - Women of a Different Light Calendar, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Word, no. 2, undated (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Zack Magazine, vol. 1, no. 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 204)
  - Oversize
    - Bad Attitude: A Lesbian Sex Magazine, vol. 1, no. 1, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 205)
    - Bay Area Reporter, vol. 21, no. 9, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - Chicago Outlines, vol. 1, no. 20, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Dick, nos. 12-13, 18, 29; vol. 5, no. 10, undated (Box 13, Folder 208 - 210)
    - Gay Blade, nos. 3, 7-8, undated (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - Gay Community News: Book Supplement, 2 issues, 1988, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 212)
    - Gay World, vol. 1, nos. 11-13, undated (Box 13, Folder 213)
    - Icon [previously Dykespeak ], 1995 1995 (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - The San Francisco Bay Times, vol. 12, no. 3; vol. 13, nos. 7, 20; vol. 14, no. 10, 1990-1993 (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - San Francisco Examiner, 5 issues, 1989, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 216)
    - San Francisco Sentinel, vol. 18, no 39, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 217)
    - The San Francisco Sphere, no. 1, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 218)
    - Sin Bros, nos. 2, 6, 1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 219)
    - The Village Voice, vol. 35, no. 33; vol. 37, no. 26, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 220)
    - The Washington Blade, vol. 22, no. 46, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 221)
  - Audio material: "Barbary Coast" and "The Party" ["Miss" Rae Bourbon], n.d., a 45 record from Lasses Record Co. [To make an appointment to hear this material, contact Historical Sound Recordings where this item is housed.]
- Additional Material, 1971-1997; Accession 2006-M-064
  - Birth Control Handbook, 1971 July (Box 1)
  - Bitch, no. 15, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Caught Looking: Feminism, Pornography & Censorship, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Compiling Social Indicators on the Situation of Women [a publication of the United Nations], 1984 (Box 1)
  - Connexions, nos. 3, 10, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Descent to the Roses of the Family [Judy Grahn], 1986 (Box 1)
  - Dykes Ain't Pretty [April Citizen Kane], 1987 (Box 1)
  - Hot Wire, vol. 1, nos. 1, 3; vol. 3, no. 2-vol. 7, no. 2; vol. 8, no. 3-vol. 9, no. 2; vol. 10, no. 2, 1984-1994 (Box 1)
  - Housework [Joan Larkin], 1975 (Box 2)
  - Malachite & Agate: Lesbian Poetry, 1997 (Box 2)
  - New York City Lesbian Health Fair journals [3 issues], 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 2)
  - No Apologies, no. 4, 1985 spring (Box 2)
  - The Olivetree Review, no. 2, 1984 winter (Box 2)
  - Out in the World [Shelley Anderson], 1991 (Box 2)
  - Palm of Your Hand, undated (Box 2)
  - Portrait [Claudia Scott], 1974 (Box 2)
  - Shades of Jade [Val Colbrook; includes associated correspondence and clipping], 1980 (Box 2)
  - Songs from a Free Space, undated (Box 2)
  - Stories of a Homeland and Other Poems [Louise Moore], 1985 (Box 2)
  - Studies in Interpretation, vol. 2, undated (Box 2)
  - Visibilities, vol. 5, no. 4, 1991 Jul/August (Box 2)
  - Voices, vol. 4, 1993 fall (Box 2)
  - Woman of Power, nos. 2, 5, 1985 summer, 1987 winter (Box 2)
  - Womantide [8 issues], 1982-1985 (Box 2)
  - Your Health Care in Crisis, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Untitled book of poetry, undated (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1981; Accession 2016-M-023
  - Lesbians Rising: Lesbian Feminist Newspaper, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)